A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Catalogs and Directories FA207
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Catalogs and Directories
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA207
7.2 Cubic Feet 6 record storage cartons
All materials are duplicate publications.
File Plan
Former Classification: I 455
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Boxes 1-5 were received from Mary Galgan, RU Library, December 1984. Accretions received as transferred.
Arrangement
Material is primarily arranged as received.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Medical education; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Catalogs and Directories
  - The Rockefeller Institute: Research Faculty Activities Publication Financial Summary, 1960-1961 and 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller Institute: Bulletin 1963-1964 to 1971-1972 Directory, 1963-1972; 9 copies (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory Academic and non-Academic Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty, Students and Administration, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1969-1970; spiral (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1970-1971; spiral (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book, 1972-1973 to 1980-1981; 9 spiral copies (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1969-1970 to 1973-1974; 5 copies (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller Institute: Catalogue Issue, 1958-1959 to 1978-1979; 19 copies (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller University: Annual Report 1969-1970, 1976-1977 & 1977-1978, 1969-1978; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research: Description of the Building and Addresses Delivered at the Opening of the Laboratories, 1906 May 11; 2 Soft Cover copies (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research: Description of the Building and Addresses Delivered at the Opening of the Laboratories, 1906 May 11; hard Cover (Box 2)
  - Addresses-Dinner in Honor of Dr. Cole, 1938 April 30 (Box 2)
  - Shaw, Albert. The American. "Review of Reviews", 1921 January (Box 2)
  - Report on the Second International Conference on the Standardization of Science and serological Tests of the Health Committee of the League of Nations, 1922 November 20-26 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Suggestion for the Preparation of Manuscripts, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Memorial meeting for Simon Flexner, 1946 June 12 (Box 2)
  - Address of Welcome: Twelfth General Assembly of the International Science Radio Union. By Detlev W. Bronk, 1957 September 5 (Box 2)
  - The Message of Science: Presented at the Universal and International Exposition at Brussels. By Paul A. Weiss, 1958 June 25 (Box 2)
  - The John's Hopkins University and the Rockefeller Institute: Allies in the March of Science. By George W. Corner, 1959 April 3 (Box 2)
  - "Medical Utopias". René J. Dubos, 1959 (Box 2)
  - "Comparative Medicine". By Richard E. Shope, 1959 October 3 (Box 2)
  - Convocation for the Conferring of Degrees, 1960 June 10; 3 copies (Box 2)
  - "Philosophy in America Today." John E. Smith, 1961 November 8 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Bulletin Financial Report, 1966 June 30 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Annual Report. 1970-1971 to 1977-1978, 1970-1978; 10 copies (Box 2)
  - Recollections of Detlev W. Bronk, 1976 February 18 (Box 2)
  - The Future of Biomedical Research and Education, 1978 October 16 (Box 2)
  - Report to the President, 1977-1978; 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Report to the President, 1977-1978; 3 copies (Box 2)
  - Report to the President, 1977-1978; 3 copies (Box 2)
  - A Notable Career in Finding Out Peyton Rous, 1879-1970; 5 copies (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Financial Report, 1974 June 30 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Financial Report, 1978 June 30; 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Alfred Nobel and The Nobel Prizes, 1968; 3 copies (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Publications, 1962-1968; 2 copies (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Story. Pro Bono Humani Generis, 1970 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: An Anniversary Album, 1976 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Beyond Tomorrow: Trends and Prospects in Medical Science, 1976 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Institute to University, 1976 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graphic Services Hand-Book, 1979 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty - Students and Administration, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty - Students and Administration, 1980-1981; 2 copies (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Faculty and Student Handbook, 1980 May (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1982 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Telephone Book and Mail Box Numbers, 1982 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller Hospital, 1982 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University Founders Ball, 1985 May 23 (Box 2)
  - RU Folder Contents. New Initiatives in Biological and Medical Science 1983, and "Rockefeller's Brain Trust: The Most Exclusive University in the World." Town and Country. Vol. 136 No. 5029, 1982 September-1983 (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. History, Organization, Present Scope of the Scientific Work Building and Equipment Publications, 1936 and 1937; 1 copy (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. Descriptive Pamphlet. 7 Copies, 1939-1940 to 1950-1951, and 1 Copy of 1952, 53, and 54, 1939-1953; 7 copies, and 1 copy (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Presentation of the George M. Kober Medal S. Gasser by Detlev W. Bronk, 1954 May 5 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller Institute Bulletin. Descriptive Pamphlet, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller Institute Bulletin. Descriptive Pamphlet, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: On the Economic and Social Contributions of Life Insurance to the Nation. The Viewpoint of the Scientist. By Detlev W. Bronk, 1959 July 28 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Medical Utopias. René J. Dubos, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: The message of Science. By Paul Weiss, 1959 June 25 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: The Johns Hopkins University and The Rockefeller Institute. Allies in the March of Science. By George W. Corner, 1959 April 31 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Comparative Medicine. By Richard E. Shope, 1959 October 3 (Box 3)
  - Conference of Biological Editors and the American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1959 December (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Philosophy in America Today. By John E. Smith, 1961 November 8 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Francis Bacon, the Advocate of Science. By Lord Adrian, 1961 April 19 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Mathematics: Its Trends and Tensions. Mark Kac, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Barklie McKee Henry., 1902-1966 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller Institute: Telephone Directory, 1959 February (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller Institute: Telephone Directory, 1959 October (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1968 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1967-1968; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Dubos, René. "The Human Environment in Technological Societies." The Rockefeller University Review., 1968 July-August; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Fairfield Osborn, 1887-1969; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: The Promise of the Future., 1970s, undated; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Occasional Papers: Reminiscences of Anthony J. Campo. Anniversary Dinner, 1970 April 9; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: David Rockefeller, The First Quarter-Century., 1950-1975; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - "Institute to University" The Rockefeller University, 1976 June 8 (Box 3)
  - "Les Prix Nobel 1975" Stockholm, 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Program in Reproductive Biology. Progress Report, 1977 January-1978 June (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Faculty and Student Handbook (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University Catalogue, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - Peyton Rous Centennial. "A Transmissible Avian Neoplasm (Sarcoma of the Common Fowl)" (Box 3)
  - The Journal of Experimental Medicine, Volume 150, 729-754, 1979 October; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory. Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Scientific and Educational Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1978-1979; 4 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1980-1981; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University Hospital: Environment for Discovery., 1981 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University; Telephone Book and Mail Box Numbers, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: A Special Place., 1981 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory. Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Roster., 1980 (Box 3)
  - University Associates Philanthropic Foundation. An Affiliate of The Rockefeller University, 1982 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: New Initiatives in Biological and Medical Science., 1983; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: 1983-1985 Scientific and Educational Programs., 3 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates. RUnion, 1959-1984 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Group Life Insurance Plan, 1985 January; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University Hospital: The Bridge between Science and Healing, undated (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: An Evolution of Excellence. By David Rockefeller., 1984 June 11 (Box 3)
  - The Rockefeller University: Convocation for Conferring Degrees, 1985 June 13; 2 copies (Box 3)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1971-1972; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - A Guide for Graduates Students at The Rockefeller University, 1977-1978; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1970-1971; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Graduate Fellows, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1968-1969 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1972-1973 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1974 1976 1977 1978 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University Bulletin: Directory, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Trustees' Luncheon, Tuesday, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Hall, 1968 June 11 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory, 1971-1972; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory, 1972-1973; 3 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory, 1973-1974; 3 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Annual Report, 1970-1971 1972-1973 1975-1976 1977-1978; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University Bulletin: Catalogue, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Catalogue, 1971-1972 and 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Catalogue, 1974-1975 to 1978-1979; 7 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1972-1973; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1973-1974; 3 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1974-1975; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1975-1976; 3 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1976-1977; 5 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1977-1978; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Report of the President, 1978-1979; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Convocation for Conferring Degrees, 1978 June 14 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1974-1975; 4 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1975-1976; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1976-1977; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1977-1978; 3 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory Faculty, Students, and Administration, 1978-1979; 2 copies (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Faculty, and Student Handbook, 1971 1974 1978 1982 (Box 4)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory of Faculty, and Graduate Fellows, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1971-1972; 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Photographic Directory, 1973-1974; 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Research, Faculty Activities, Publications, Financial Summary, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Research, Faculty Activities, Publications, Financial Summary, 1961-1962 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Stock Catalogue, 1970; 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1966 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1970-1971; 2 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1973-1974; 4 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1974-1975; 3 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1975-1976; 3 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Directory, 1976-1977; 3 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book and Mail Box Numbers, 1977-1978; 4 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book and Mail Box Numbers, 1978-1979; 4 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book and Mail Box Numbers, 1979-1980; 3 copies (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book and Mail Box Numbers, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book Academic and Non-Academic Staff, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University: Telephone Book Academic and Non-Academic Staff, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - Scientific Instruments: Caspary Gallery of The Rockefeller University, 1976 (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University: 75th Anniversary Reunion, Program, 1976 June 6-9; 2 copies (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1991 (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1981; 2 copies (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller Institute Hospital, 1910-1955 (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University: Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University: Annual Report, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller University faculty and Student Handbook: Fifth Edition (Box 6)
  - Convocation Programs, 1975-1985 1990; Paige box (Box 6)
  - Reception for New Members of the Faculty and New Students, 1966 October 17; Paige box (Box 6)
  - Financial Report, 1966 June 30; Paige box (Box 6)
  - Catalogue, 1960, 1966, 1970-1979; Paige box (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller Hospital - A Collection of Staff Photos, 1910-1981; Paige box (Box 6)
  - The Rockefeller Institute Bulletin, 1956-1957, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University Faculty and Staff Handbook (fifth edition) (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1959-2004 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller University: Directory of Graduates, 2000-2001 (Box 6)